<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on The Mysterious Larks</title>
    <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on The Mysterious Larks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:55 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Team Management: What is causing Communication Breakdown</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explores the causes of communication breakdown in virtual teams - Makes the point that it is more than just language barriers (English as a first language). There is a critical need for trust, leaders who are flexible and capable of dealing with contradictions and dealing with the impact that a lack of incidental meeting and language norms introduce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Manager’s Guide to Virtual Teams</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look at virtual teams from the perspective of a manager. Looks at Cultural. Logistical and Communication gaps. Intro - 3 stages of Virtual Team Development - Setting up - Context Communication, definitions and challenges - Accountability - Defusing Conflict - Delivering a Product - Cross Cultural - Futures&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Team Effectiveness: A Proposed Research Agenda</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniting the Virtual Workforce: Transforming Leadership and Innovation in the Globally Integrated Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Physical Book (Available at the Matheson Library at Monash). An in depth of Virtual Distance, the focus of Managing Virtual Distance (Chapter 5) and exploring Technology and the Future in chapter 9 and 10.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leading Virtual Project Teams</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explores the intrinsic connection between Leadership and Communication in light of new communication methods and Virtual Teams. Of particular interest is the focus on e-Leadership (Chapter 2), Enhancing Virtual Project Communications (Chapter 3) and Cultural Communication Issues (Chapter 4).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Virtual Teams</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Teams provide advantages in flexibility and overcoming barriers faced by traditional team formats. Despite this Virtual Teams also provide new challenges and difficulties to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hundreds of students living in remote and rural parts of Australia are being left behind because of slow Internet speeds and data caps</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:21:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Particular areas in the world do not get the same quality internet as the more corporate areas of the world. This may be due to ISPs not being motivated enough to cover these areas well due to the lack of customers. The difference in download/upload speeds between clients can result in a choppy conference call or continuous call drops. This news report focuses on how the bad coverage affects education for children, but the same concepts can be applied to virtual team communications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Skype blocked in certain countries</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 22:18:10 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article discusses why some countries decide to block all traffic from particular virtual communication sources and how to bypass their firewalls. Using these techniques may be illegal in some countries, so you may not be acting in the most professional manner in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers to Adopting Technology for Teaching and Learning</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 22:03:02 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a study done over a decade ago on how the learning environment changed as new technology was rolled in. While it is a bit dated, the points relevant to our topic are still valid today. It discusses how the learning curve can slow things down and how failure of systems is a major problem in getting things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Barriers to Communication</title>
      <link>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 22:03:02 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://the-mysterious-larks.github.io/post/resource-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the communication challenges faced by a wide range of industries brought on by globalization. It is not specific to technological barriers but it is a good place to start to have a general understanding of the issues faced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>